Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials, 1956-2018 RL.10006_AV RL.10006_AV
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal and Associated Audiovisual Resources, 1956-2017; 1; 70 items
  The Personal and Associated Audiovisual Resources, 1956-2017, series includes 8mm home movies, phonodisc home recordings, and a variety of resources relating to Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel's interests and career.
  - Phonotone; 33 1/3 rpm long play; Recording of Our Wedding; Barbara and Alan; Hotel DelMonico; July 22, 1956; New York, Part 1, side 1 and 2, 1956-07-22 (Box 66, Audio-disc RL10006-PD-0001)
  - Phonotone; 33 1/3 rpm long play; Recording of Our Wedding; Barbara and Alan; Hotel DelMonico; July 22, 1956; New York, Part 1, side 3 and 4, 1956-07-22 (Box 66, Audio-disc RL10006-PD-0002)
  - Phonotone; 33 1/3 rpm long play; Recording of Our Wedding; Barbara and Alan; Hotel DelMonico; July 22, 1956; New York, Part 2, side 1 and 2, 1956-07-22 (Box 66, Audio-disc RL10006-PD-0003)
  - Phonotone; 33 1/3 rpm long play; Recording of Our Wedding; Barbara and Alan; Hotel DelMonico; July 22, 1956; New York, Part 2, side 3 and 4, 1956-07-22 (Box 66, Audio-disc RL10006-PD-0004)
  - Haitti # 2; Excellent, 1956-08-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0003)
  - Haitti # 2; OK, 1956-08-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0004)
  - Dominican Republic; OK, 1956-08-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0005)
  - Puerto Rice #2; Fair, 1956-08-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0006)
  - Puerto Rice #4; Hotel DelMonico; good; starts at DelMonico, 1956-08-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0007)
  - Puerto Rice #3; Excellent, 1956-08-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0008)
  - New Hampshire; 16 feet only, 1958-10-25 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0009)
  - Puerto Rice #1; Good, 1956-08-24 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0010)
  - Monrow, NY; Wentworth, NH; good, Circa 1956 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0002)
  - [illegible]; Wmsbg; [illegible], Circa 1956 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0012)
  - Sis's Party; Barbara's Party; Private, 1957-05-02 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0001)
  - C'vlle Snow - N.N.; sis & Joe Hunt. Park; BL & Judy - (Alan), 1958-02-21 (Box 182, Film-reel RL10006-8mm-0011)
  - But Not on My Block: CBS News, 1976-01 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0041)
  - Tape of Eric Wallace; Natasha Conn Interviews; and Pas de Deux; filmed 12/79-shown 1/80; channel 7 KQED-Anchorage, 1979-12 (Box 69, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0199)
  - After Rubens, Lamp Unto My Feet, CBS-TV, narrated by Barbaralee Diamonstein, 1977; 00:28:07 (Box AV-006, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0083)
    View on YouTube.
  - Soho Interiors: Ten O'Clock News, Tuesday, 1982-10-19 (Box 1, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0014)
  - Good Morning America, 1983-11-24 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0013)
  - Saturday Morning, 1983-12-10 (Box 70, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0212)
  - One Thousand Years in thy Sight: The Ashkenaz Show: CBS, 1986-06-08 (Box 70, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0210)
  - Remaking America: The Today Show, 1986-11 (Box 69, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0208)
  - Chihuly: Glass Master, 1988 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0272)
  - Reception for the American Foundation of the Royal Academy of Music in the presence of Her Royal Highness the Princess of Wales, 1989-02-03 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0266)
  - CNN Future Watch, 1992-01-18 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0273)
  - Big Apple Circus; Greetings from Coney Island, Lincoln Center 1991-1992, 1992-04-01 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0267)
  - Clinton/Gore for President "The Man from Hope", 1992-07-21 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0264)
  - The Presidential Inauguration, 1992 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0269)
  - Huffington Republican Congress, circa 1992 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0265)
  - Smithsonian Folkways Workers at the White House, circa 1992 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0271)
  - Book Review by Michele Ross of Inside the Art World: Conversations with Barbaralee Diamonstein: CNN Morning News, 1994-04-08 (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0255)
  - NBC Nightly News, 1996-05-08 (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0253)
  - Ifill, Gwen: Clinton Fundraiser Segment: NBC Nightly News, 1996-05-09 (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0254)
  - New York Closeup, 1998-05-12 (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0262)
  - 92 St. Y Unterberg Poetry Center: "In The Poet's Own Voice", 1998 (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0256)
  - Ambassador: Inside the Embassy, 2002 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0013)
  - A Place of Our Own, a film by Stanley Nelson, 2004 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0051)
  - Beyond Brown: Pursuing the promise, 2004 (Box 755, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0053)
  - Sweet Honey in the Rock: Raise your voice, a film by Stanley Nelson, 2005 (Box 755, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0054)
  - Jonestown: the life and death of Peoples Temple, a film by Stanley Nelson, 2007 (Box 755, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0056)
  - Freedom Riders, a film by Stanley Nelson, 2011 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0052)
  - I Love NY 2012 Summer/Fall Television Campaign (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0024)
  - Freedom Summer, Mississippi 1964, American Experience Films press copy, 2014-06-24 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0050)
  - A Gift from Jacques: A Dance as a Gift (7: 30); Memorial and Celebration for Shaun O'Brien and Cris Alexander (39: 00), including booklet, "Eight Poems", 2014 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0046)
  - ABMC U.S. Memorial New Zealand, Generator Studio and Fischer Bouma Partnership LLC, disc 1, 2014 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0048)
  - Freedom Summer, Mississippi 1964, American Experience Films, 2014 (Box 755, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0057)
  - The National Mall: America's Front Yard, a National Geographic Special for PBS, 2015-04-21 (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0047)
  - Opening of the Diamonstein-Spielvogel Papers with John Palfrey, 2016-04-07 (Digital-materials SET-0001, Video-file RL10006-MP4-0002)
  - Video Message from Dr. Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel and Ambassador Carl Spielvogel to NGO/Bratislava, Slovakia, ACEC (Association for Culture, Education and Communication), 2017-11-08 (Digital-materials SET-0001, Video-file RL10006-MP4-0004)
  - A Conversation with Ari Melber -- The Diamonstein-Spielvogel Forum on History and the Public Good, 2019-10-19 (Digital-materials SET-0001, Audio-file RL10006-MP3-0001)
  - A Conversation with Martin Baron -- The Diamonstein-Spielvogel Forum on History and the Public Good, 2020-10-22 (Digital-materials SET-0001, Audio-file RL10006-MP4-0012)
  - For Barbaralee. B-roll of painted lamps and people admiring them on display, undated (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0261)
  - Spielvogel Home Southampton, undated (Box 661, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0277)
  - Spielvogel House, undated (Box 661, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0276)
  - Ball, Untitled Recording, undated (Box 73, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0247)
  - Big Apple Circus: Walden--A Place to Create, undated (Box 43, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0268)
  - Bill Moyers Buying the War, undated (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0029)
  - Bill Moyers LBJ Tapes, undated (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0028)
  - Bill Moyers Sandy Hook, undated (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0027)
  - New York Landmark Preservation; Philippe de Montebello; "Chrysler Building"; Itzhak Perlman; "Metropolitan Museum of Art", undated (Box 71, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0223)
  - Fields of Honor, undated (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0004)
  - New York City and Beyond Tape 1, undated (Box 68, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0184)
  - New York City and Beyond Tape 2, undated (Box 68, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0185)
  - New York City and Beyond Tape 3, undated (Box 68, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0186)
  - New York City and Beyond Tape 4, undated (Box 68, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0187)
  - News: B. Spielvogel, undated (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0258)
  - Service Arts Promotional Video, undated (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0260)
  - Treasures of New York: The New York Botanical Garden, undated (Box 661, Video-disc RL10006-DVD-0025)
  - Untitled: School children read poetry, undated (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0257)
  - Wengate on Acconce, undated (Box 74, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0248)